Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you,
you are watching U D Real, I am
your own personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma. The
title of today's video goes to this gentleman
's comment. Now, he has
not written his real name in the comment, due to which we are not using his
name but thank you.
If you also want that
videos should come on the channel daily as per your comment, then
tell us in the comment section with your name
and if you are watching the video for the first time on the channel, then
join us,
like the video, share it and subscribe to the channel.
Regular videos will be available for you daily as per your suggestions, questions
and comments.
So let's start today's video and
know the information about the vision and development of Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited.
This plan is a non-
lending participating life insurance plan.
Now if we understand this line in our own words, then
see, 'Nordin' means that the
premium that we will pay to the company, whatever
we understand and take as per our age, on that
basis the company will not
invest that premium directly in equity stocks,
so the
risk related to that will not be on us, that is, the
return on a fortune will not be  It becomes
guaranteed which we can understand further
now it is participating it means
that every year at the end of the financial year
the company will announce a bonus which can be more or less
and with this
our life insurance will remain the same during the policy term because this is a
life insurance plan okay yes in what
manner the benefits will be received we will
understand later now let us talk about the information of the benefit so first of all
what is the benefit in this
because it is an endowment plan so there is a
direct maturity benefit
what will we get on maturity sum majority along with
bonus and terminal bonus along with it okay
if the company announces it then we will get it
now what is this sum majority
in sum majority means maturity in sum majority
means whatever base premium we pay
we will get it on maturity
right back and cute bonus means
simple reversionary bonus which will be received every year
which will accumulate through positive now
you will get terminal bonus either on death in case of
death or you will get it at the maturity
time in case of center  In this,
only the company can tell, right, now the
next benefit is death benefit
because these are life insurance, when if it is
sum assured on death,
along with that, you get accurate bonus till the date of death
and along with that, you also get terminal bonus.
Now the death benefit here is given together to the
nominee and the policy gets cancelled.
Now the question has come that what is sum assured on death
here, so see, there are two options in the plan for death
benefit, first
option number A in which it is being said that you will get
10 times your annual premium
or the news which you will choose will be the same,
then option number B in which it is said
that you will get 150% of the award or
10% of the annual premium,
now whatever you choose while taking the plan, the
same will be understood here,
you will see one more condition written in the plan, that is, the
minimum death
benefit will
not be less than 105% of the total paid premium under any condition.  If we have
come to Surendra then we have to pay premium for at least 2 years
continuously, for this we
can take Surendra policy. If we
talk about Guaranteed Cylinder Value, then Guaranteed
Cylinder Value factor will be multiplied by the
total paid premium i.e.
20 times the premium. Then
whatever bonus we have accumulated will be added to it by
multiplying the Guaranteed Cylinder Value factor of the bonus on the bonus. Now
he has commented but a
lot of information is missing in this comment
like we do not know the premium payment term
and we do not know which
option he has taken. We
take the example of the policy brochure here
and will do the basic calculation on the basis of whatever figure
we have.
Sir, the same age is 35 years, he is taking a positive term of 20 years, he has taken the
premium payment of 10 years, he has taken the basic sub-match and
Rs 2.5 lakh here and the
death benefit option is
selected here i.e. 10 times the basic or annual
premium. Now the
basic understanding of the mother is that she is taking and taking it, so
in such a situation the annual premium  The basic will be Rs 18430, we will
pay this. Okay, now tell me, it is
more than Rs 1 lakh and the premium
payment term is between 7 years to 15
years, so in such a situation, I am telling you the bonus rate
in the last 2 years, it has been
Rs 36 against Rs 1000
and it was
3.6% last year, the rate was
Rs 33.50 against Rs 1000
today, that is, 3.35 percent
basic understanding and okay, so now we are assuming the
average bonus rate here is 3 percent, right, if the
positive term is of 20 years, then 2.5 lakh will yield 3 percent
and you multiply it by 20, then the
term bonus here will be 2 lakh.
Okay, now the matter has come to the
terminal bonus, so the rate of terminal bonus
given to us was the same last year as well as
before that, it was at the rate of Rs 1250, that
is  That is,
1.5% of our short is ₹2.5 lakh, if we take out one decimal two
five percent here then 3125 will be the
terminal bonus, your
maturity benefit is
₹300, what will happen in the maturity benefit, we will add a bonus of 1.5 lakh to it
and add the terminal bonus, so the
maturity benefit here will be approximately 3 lakh
37425, which is
₹184300, you remember I had said that there is
understanding and two maturity, we take the
right equal to the premium we paid, now
sir, if only one death occurs after
completion of 10 years of the policy, then in
such a situation the understanding and we give here is of
2.5 lakh, that is, the basic benefit,
we have taken option number A here
and we had already made this huge, now due to the
fear of 3 percent, the bonus that will be accumulated in 10 years will be
75000 and the
rate of terminal bonus is the same  It will be applied
here because this is the announcer, so the
terminal bonus is ₹3125. Now if we
add it here, then our death benefit here will be
₹70000. Our terminal bonus is ₹
30125. We have added everything together, so the
benefit here is ₹328125. Now we consider,
Sir, we are taking the policy as soon as 2 years of the policy are
completed,
so how much total premium will we pay here in 2 years?
18430 * 2 = 36860.
And how much bonus will be collected here in 2 years, it is a
simple reversal, if we
take out 3% of the bonus of 25 lakhs and multiply it by two, then a
bonus of ₹15000 will be collected. Now we will do the
video on the full screen
because the Guaranteed Surendra Value Factor has been added on top of our screen,
which will be
applied on the total paid premium. We have
taken a positive term of 20 years, our two years are
completed. Now you can see here whether you are taking a term of
10 years or not.  If you take a policy term of 11 years, 12 to 22 years, then if the
total
paid premium is for two years, then the
Guaranteed Surrender Value Factor of 30 will be
applicable, right, that means only 30 will be applicable.
Keep the video on full screen
because now the factors that are being added will be
applied to our bonus, that means the
Guaranteed Surrender Value
Factor that will be applied for the bonus is on top of our screen.
We have taken a policy term of 20 years,
we have completed two years. If
our policy term was 15 years, then the
added Guaranteed Surrender Value Factor here would have been applicable
only for the bonus, but if we have
taken a positive term of 20 years, then it is right.
Now we get the figure here that the Guaranteed
Surrender Value Factor is
30% for the total paid premium and the Guaranteed
Surrender Value Factor is 2% for the bonus,
so the total paid premium
will be Rs 36860 less 30% and 2% of Rs 15000 which is our
bonus only will be added, then the
amount will be Rs 11358.  So now we have come to know
how much loss there is in buying a cylinder
in the beginning, that is why we should understand everything,
now see till here the video is as per their comments,
still a lot of details
remain, like eligibility
criteria, loan reduction, what are the benefits of paid up policy, there are
some basic terms and
conditions that also need to be known, so we will know in the next part so that there is
no overloading of information because calculations will have to be done, if there were
too many calculations then
many people get confused,
we have received your feedback in the comment section,
you watched the video inside,
thank you very much for that, understand one thing,
explain to others also that insurance
protection is never taken incomplete and stay
connected with us for such regular videos
because we bring absolutely free videos for you
and subscribing to the channel
is also absolutely free,
thank you very much, thank you very much to all of you